Dinesh kumar

MERN Stack Developer

About Me

I am a skilled Full Stack Web Developer with expertise in frontend (HTML, CSS, JavaScript ,React,Next.js) and backend (Node.js, Express) technologies. also 7+ months experience as a Frontend developer(Next js,React js) at MyPustak, Their problem-solving abilities, commitment to clean code, and effective communication make them a valuable asset in creating exceptional web applications.

Professional Experience

React Js Full Stack Developer, Technix Technology

Jun 2024 – present Patna, India

 Developing and maintaining web applications using React. Collaborating with crossfunctional teams to design and implement new features. Ensuring high performance and responsiveness of applications. Working with RESTful APIs and backend services to integrate functionalities.

Software Development Engineer, Mypustak.com Link ☑

Oct 2023 – May 2024 Kolkata, West Bengal

In few month as a Software developer, I mastered HTML, CSS, and JavaScript,React.js, Next.js collaborating on agile projects. Achieved Projects experience in creating responsive and visually appealing websites.

Education

Bachlor Of Computer Application, Magadh University Bodhgaya

Aug 2019 - Aug 2022

Gaya, India

Senior Secondary, Gurua Collage Gurua

2017 – 2019 Gurua, india

Skills

HTML5 | CSS3 | JavaScript | React Js | Next.js | Redux-toolkit | Tailwind CSS |

Bootstrap 5 | Rest Api | MUI | Node.Js | Express.Js | MongoDB | Git | C programming |

HackerRank — 2 Stars

Courses

Full Stack Web Development (MERN), Prepbytes Link 🗷

Mar 2023 - Nov 2023 Gurugram (Haryana), India

Projects

MyPustak E-Commerce Website, Link ☑

Nov 2023 - Apr 2024

- An online platform offering a wide range of new and used books at competitive prices, ensuring an easy and affordable book-buying experience.
- Tech:- Next Js, Tailwind CSS, Redux, JavaScript

MyPustak Blog Website, Link

Jan 2024 - present

- Explore book reviews, recommendations, and literary articles on the MyPustak Blog.
 Perfect for book lovers looking for their next great read!
- Tech: Next Js, Tailwind CSS, TypeScript, Redux-Toolkit,

Internship

Mobile App Development, Brikbond Shopping App

Dec 2022 - Feb 2023

Tech Stack: Java, XML, Firebase Realtime Database, Firebase Firestore, OTP Verification with Firebase Authentication, Razorpay payment gateway integration etc

This Android App totally work likes flipcart & Mesho Shopping Apps